A Register of the Juan Lechin Oquendo Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Juan Lechín Oquendo Papers
1952-2002
2004C14
Lechín Oquendo, Juan.
21 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (8.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The papers provide an overview of the life and career of a prominent Bolivian trade unionist and politician, Juan Lechín Oquendo who served as head of the powerful Central Obrera Boliviana for 35 years (1952-1987), and was vice president of Bolivia from 1960-1964. Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, studies, copies of government documents and trade union records, printed matter, sound recordings of interviews, photographs, and memorabilia in the papers relate to miners' unions in Bolivia and the Central Obrera Boliviana, the Bolivian revolution of 1952, as well as subsequent political and economic developments in Bolivia.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2004
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biography Note
1914 May 18 Born, Corocoro, Bolivia
1944 Elected general secretary, Federación Sindical de Trabajadores Mineros de Bolivia (FSTMB)
1952 Participates in Bolivian National Revolution as a member of the Movimiento Nacionalista Revolucionario (MNR), and is named Minister of Mines. Becomes Executive Secretary of the Central Obrera Boliviana (COB)
1960 Elected vice-president of Bolivia
1964 Leaves MNR and forms the Partido Revolucionario de Izquierda Nacional (PRIN)
1965-1971 In political exile
1971 Returns to Bolivia and is active in the creation of the Asamblea Popular
1972-1978 In political exile
1980 Runs unsuccessfully for president as candidate of the PRIN
1987 Retires as leader of the FSTMB and COB
2000 Author, Memorias
2001 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
Acquired in 2004, the Juan Lechín Oquendo papers in the Hoover Institution Archives provide an overview of the life and career of a prominent Bolivian trade unionist and politician. Lechín Oquendo served as head of the powerful Central Obrera Boliviana for 35 years (1952-1987), and in this capacity he not only defended the interests of Bolivian workers, but became involved in the turbulent politics of his country. At various times, Lechín Oquendo served as government minister, as vice-president of Bolivia, and as the leader of an important opposition party. During several periods of military rule in Bolivia, Lechín Oquendo was forced into political exile.
There are significant biographical materials in the papers. In addition to numerous clippings, the Biographical File contains a number of writings on Lechín Oquendo, including a major biography. The Speeches and Writings series contains Lechín Oquendo's autobiography, and in the Sound Recordings series there are a number of extensive interviews with him. The Photographs series contains a large number of prints depicting Lechín Oquendo, including many relating to his political and trade union activities.
The Political Parties and Trade Unions File is comprised largely of publications by Bolivian political parties and trade unions, including the organizations that Lechín Oquendo was affiliated with: the Central Obrera Boliviano, the Federacíon Sindical de Trabjadores Mineros de Bolivia, and the Partido Revolucionario de Izquierdo. Materials about the Bolivian economy, and especially its mining sector, can be found in the Subject File.
The Juan Claudio Lechín Weise File is devoted to Lechín Oquendo's son, and consists primarily of his published writings. The Printed Matter series consists largely of publications relating to Bolivian politics and history, with an emphasis on the National Revolution of 1952.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into 11 series: Biographical File, Correspondence, Speeches and Writings, Political Parties and Trade Unions File, Juan Claudio Lechín Weise File, Subject File, Writings by Others, Printed Matter, Photographs, Sound Recordings, and Oversize Materials
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Central Obrera Boliviana.; Labor unions--Bolivia.; Miners--Bolivia.; Bolivia--History--Revolution, 1952.; Bolivia--Politics and government.; Bolivia--Economic conditions.; Phonotapes.
Container List
- Biographical File, 1946-2001.
  Biographies, clippings, genealogical history, legal records, personal documents, programs, questionnaires, resolutions, and scrapbook materials, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Biographies and other writings about Juan Lechín Ochendo
    - Anonymous
      - "Lechin,", undated. (Folder 1: 1)
        Typescript
      - "La verdad historica de la obra revolucionaria de Lechín,", undated. (Folder 1: 2)
      - Untitled fragment, undated. (Folder 1: 3)
    - Balcazar, Jaime
      - "El Maestro Juan Lechín,", 1988. (Folder 1: 4)
      - "Biografias cruzadas,", 1990. (Folder 1: 5)
    - Cajias, Lupe, "Historia de una leyenda"
      - Notes and research materials, 1986 (Folder 1: 6)
      - Typescript fragment, 1988 (Folder 1: 7)
      - Typescript
        - Volume one, 1988 (Folder 1: 8)
        - Volume two, 1988 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - Calla, Ricardo, La derrota de Lechín, 1986. (Folder 2: 2)
      Printed copy
    - Mariaca Iturri, Gabriel and Guillermo, "Cambio de guardia: El entierro de Lechín,", 2001 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Clippings
    - 1946-1951 (Folder 2: 4)
    - 1952-1959 (Folder 2: 5)
    - 1960-1964 (Folder 2: 6)
    - 1965 (Folder 2: 7)
    - 1970 (Folder 2: 8-9)
    - 1971-1985 (Folder 2: 10)
    - 1986 (Folder 2: 11)
    - 1988-1998 (Folder 2: 12)
  - Genealogical history of the Lechín family, 1998 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Legal records pertaining to a dispute over the nationality of Juan Lechín Oquendo, 1965-1966 (Folder 3: 2)
  - Personal documents
    - Birth certificates, 1986 (Folder 3: 3)
    - Certificate of military service, 1985 (Folder 3: 4)
    - Certificate of release from detention, 1957 (Folder 3: 5)
    - Employment records, 1988 (Folder 3: 6)
    - Passports, 1981-1991 (Folder 3: 7)
  - Programs, 1961 (Folder 3: 8)
  - Questionnaires with answers provided by Juan Lechín Oquendo, undated (Folder 3: 9)
  - Resolutions honoring Juan Lechín Oquendo, 1985-1998 (Folder 3: 10)
  - Scrapbook materials
    - 1965 (Folder 3: 11-12)
    - 2001 (Folder 3: 13)
- Correspondence, 1952-2001. (Box 4)
  Letters and enclosures, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - General
    - A-K, 1977-2000 (Folder 4: 1)
    - L-Z, 1952-1998 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Unidentified, 1978 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Acción Democratica Nacionalista (Enrique Toro Tejada), 1998 (Folder 4: 4)
  - Aga Khan, Sadruddin, 1976 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Ampuero Diaz, Raúl Galvarino, 1976-1978 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Bassio, Lelio, 1976 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Castro Ruz, Fidel, 1985 (Folder 4: 8)
  - Central Obrera Boliviana, 1980-2001 (Folder 4: 9)
  - Confederación Sindical de Trabajadores en Construcción de Bolivia, 1986 (Folder 4: 10)
  - Conferencia Episcopal de Bolivia (Armando Gutierrez Granier, Luis Rodriguez Pardo), 1984 (Folder 4: 11)
  - Federación Sindical de Trabajadores Mineros de Bolivia, 1997-1998 (Folder 4: 12)
  - Flores Vaca, Katyamara, 1999 (Folder 4: 13)
  - Fondo Social de Emergencia, 1988 (Folder 4: 14)
  - Instituto Americano para el Desarrollo del Sindicalismo Libre (Richard V. Oulahan), 1986 (Folder 4: 15)
  - Justiniano, José, 1981 (Folder 4: 16)
  - Lechín Weise, Juan Claudio, undated (Folder 4: 17)
  - Machicado Saravia, Flavio, 1982 (Folder 4: 18)
  - Mercado Rodriguez, Gualberto, 1985 (Folder 4: 19)
  - Monroy Chazarreta, Germán, 1998 (Folder 4: 20)
  - Montero Zambrana, Amelia, 2001 (Folder 4: 21)
  - National Union of Mineworkers (J. Gormley), 1977 (Folder 4: 22)
  - Navarro Izquierdo, Fausto, 1986 (Folder 4: 23)
  - Ortiz-Patiño, Jaime, 1997-1998 (Folder 4: 24)
  - Partido Revolucionario Autentico, 1987 (Folder 4: 25)
  - Sanginés Uriarte, Mario, 1958-1998 (Folder 4: 26)
  - Strauss Ivanovic, Guido, 1976 (Folder 4: 27)
  - Vetter, Heinz Oskar, 1981 (Folder 4: 28)
- Speeches and Writings, 1954-2000.
  Articles, interviews, monographs, open letter, and speeches, arranged chronologically
  - Autobiographical writing, undated. (Folder 4: 29)
  - "¿Es necessario un partido nacionalista en el pais?", undated. (Folder 4: 30)
  - "El hombre en la filosofia,", undated. (Folder 4: 31)
    Holograph and typescript
  - "Intervencion del estado en la economia boliviana,", undated. (Folder 4: 32)
  - Interview, undated. (Folder 4: 33)
  - "Lechín-Generaldades," interview, undated. (Folder 4: 34)
  - Lechin y la Revolución Nacional, compilation of speeches, undated. (Folder 4: 35-36)
    Printed copies
  - "Mensaje de Juan Lechín a los trabajadores bolivianos,", undated. (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - "El nacionalismo obrero,", undated (Folder 5: 2)
  - Open letter to Evo Morales, undated. (Folder 5: 3)
  - "El periodo militar,", undated. (Folder 5: 4)
  - "¿Que es el nacionalismo revolucionario?", undated. (Folder 5: 5)
  - Reading notes, undated. (Folder 5: 6)
    Holograph and typescript notes
  - Speech, XX Congreso Minero, La Paz(?), Bolivia, undated. (Folder 5: 7)
  - "Testimonio,", undated. (Folder 5: 8)
  - Writing on Bolivian politics, undated. (Folder 5: 9)
    Holograph
  - Speech, Primer Congreso Nacional de Trabajadores, La Paz, Bolivia, 1954 November 1. (Folder 5: 10)
  - Speech, Tercer Congreso Nacional de Trabajadores, La Paz, Bolivia, 1962 May 3. (Folder 5: 11)
  - Response to Chilean proposal regarding Bolivia's demand for maritime access, written 1977
    - Clippings, 1977 (Folder 5: 12)
    - Typescript drafts, 1977 (Folder 5: 13)
  - "Treinta años en la linea sindical clasista,", 1982. (Folder 5: 14)
  - "A treinta años de la Revolución de Abril,", 1982 March 12. (Folder 5: 15)
  - "Digamos la verdad al pueblo," speech delivered at meeting of Bolivian mineworkers, 1983 April 25. (Folder 5: 16)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - "Mensaje a todos mis compañeros de las minas,", 1984. (Folder 5: 17)
  - Speech to mineworkers, 1986 June 4. (Folder 5: 18)
  - "Bush y su mentalidad de director de la CIA," Ultima Hora, 1990 September 6. (Folder 5: 19)
  - "El imperialismo norteamericano: ¿mesias o genocida?" Presencia, 1991 February 16. (Folder 5: 20)
  - "El PRIN a su pueblo,", 1997 May. (Folder 5: 21)
  - "Al pueblo de Bolivia, a los trajadores, militancia y simpatizantes del PRIN,", 1997 June 6. (Folder 5: 22)
  - Memorias, published 2000
    - Outline, undated (Folder 5: 23)
    - Notes, undated (Folder 5: 24)
    - Interviews
      - Undated (Folder 5: 25-26)
      - 1996 (Folder 5: 27)
    - Typescript drafts, undated (Box-folder 6: 1-5)
    - Proofs, 2000 (Folder 6: 6-7)
    - Proofs, 2000 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
    - Invitation to a presentation of the book, 2000 August (Folder 7: 3)
- Political Parties and Trade Unions File, 1946-1997.
  Bulletins, catalog, communiqués, court records, leaflets, manifestos, monographs, pamphlets, programs, reports, resolutions, serial issue, speeches, and thesis, arranged alphabetically by name of organization, and by physical form thereunder
  - Central Obrera Boliviano
    - Bulletins and communiqués, 1970-1985 (Folder 7: 4)
    - Court records, 1990. (Folder 7: 5)
      Testimony by Germán Crespo Infantes, Cayetano Llobet Tavolara, and Noel Vásquez Valdéz in a lawsuit brought by the Central Obrera Boliviana against Luis Arce Goméz, Luis Garcia Mesa, and others
    - Monograph, circa 1989. (Box-folder 8: 1)
      Lazarte, Jorge, Movimiento obrero y procesos políticos en Bolivia: Historia de la C.O.B., 1952-1987
    - Pamphlets, 1954-1987 (Folder 8: 2)
    - Reports, 1983-1997 (Folder 8: 3)
    - Resolutions, 1977-1988 (Folder 8: 4)
    - Transcript of remarks by Ramiro Carrasco and Gustavo Rodriguez, 1984 November 7 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Falange Socialista Boliviana, 1987. (Folder 8: 6)
    Proposals
  - Federación Sindical de Trabajadores Mineros de Bolivia
    - Bulletins and communiqué, 1983 (Folder 8: 7)
    - Catalog, 1992 (Folder 8: 8)
    - Monograph, 1955. (Folder 8: 9)
      Torres Calleja, Mario, A dos años de la nacionalización de las minas
    - Pamphlets, 1946-1967 (Folder 8: 10)
    - Reports and resolutions, 1978 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Movimiento Nacionalista Revolucionario
    - Communiqué, program, and serial issue, 1953-1991 (Folder 8: 12)
    - Proposal for reunification, circa 1988 (Folder 8: 13)
    - Report, 1954 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Nueva Alternativa Politica (Box 9)
    - Manifesto and program, 1987 (Folder 9: 1)
    - Reports, undated (Folder 9: 2)
    - Thesis, 1987 (Folder 9: 3)
  - Partido Revolucionario de Izquierda Nacional
    - Bulletins and communiqués, 1981-1985 (Folder 9: 4)
    - Internal documents, 1982-1985 (Folder 9: 5)
    - Leaflets, undated (Folder 9: 6)
    - Manifesto, undated (Folder 9: 7)
    - Membership cards, undated (Folder 9: 8)
    - Pamphlets, undated (Folder 9: 9)
    - Program, undated (Folder 9: 10)
    - Speeches, 1985 (Folder 9: 11)
  - Miscellaneous trade union bulletins, 1978-1985 (Folder 9: 12)
- Juan Claudio Lechín Weise File, 1980-2001.
  Clipping, correspondence, and speeches and writings of Lechín Oquendo's son, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Clipping, 1986 (Folder 9: 13)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1998 (Folder 9: 14)
  - Speeches and writings
    - "Borradores No. 1,", undated. (Folder 9: 15)
    - "Breve esbozo historica de Bolivia,", undated. (Folder 9: 16)
    - "Contexto nacional actual,", undated. (Folder 9: 17)
    - "Después de la Oscuridad,", undated. (Folder 9: 18)
    - "La espontaneidad de las masas y el rol del partido,", undated. (Folder 9: 19)
    - "La izquierda nacional,", undated. (Folder 9: 20)
    - "Proceso democratico versus Asamblea Popular,", undated. (Folder 9: 21)
    - Untitled writing on Bolivian history, undated. (Folder 9: 22)
    - Untitled writing on Bolivian political parties, undated. (Folder 9: 23)
    - Untitled writing on Bolivian politics, undated. (Folder 9: 24)
    - Untitled writing on revolutionary movements, undated. (Folder 9: 25)
    - Untitled writing on revolutionary theory, undated. (Folder 9: 26)
    - Untitled writing on the Central Obrera Boliviano, undated. (Folder 9: 27)
    - Untitled writing on Bolivian trade unions, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - "El Justiciero de la Flor-cartucho,", 1989. (Folder 10: 2)
    - El festejo del deseo, 1992. (Folder 10: 3)
    - El Al-Borak o el subdesarrollo en América Latina, 1998. (Folder 10: 4)
    - Enemigo en el alma, published in 1999
      - First version, published as Fernando, el Caótico, 1998. (Folder 10: 5)
      - Second version, 1999. (Folder 10: 6)
    - "El Instituto BSFX,", 1999. (Folder 10: 7)
    - "La venganza," in Jaime Iturri Salmón (ed.), Antología del cuento erótico boliviano, published in 2001
      - Typescript, undated (Folder 10: 8)
      - Printed copy, 2001 (Folder 10: 9)
- Subject File, 1944-1998.
  Clippings, correspondence, pamphlets, and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Agrarian reform--Bolivia, 1955 (Folder 10: 10)
  - Bolivia--Economic conditions
    - Undated (Folder 10: 11-12)
    - 1977-1978 (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - 1983 (Folder 11: 2)
    - 1984-1990 (Folder 11: 3)
    - 1993-1995 (Folder 11: 4)
    - 1995-1996 (Folder 11: 5)
  - Bolivia--Politics and government
    - Undated (Folder 11: 6-7)
    - 1944-1952 (Folder 11: 8)
    - 1953-1974 (Folder 11: 9)
    - 1975-1998 (Folder 11: 10)
  - Bolivia. Congreso Nacional. Cámara de Senadores, 1987 (Folder 11: 11)
  - Brazil--Politics and government, undated (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Chile--Politics and government, 1973-1977 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Coca production
    - Undated (Folder 12: 3-4)
    - 1983-1988 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Cuba--Politics and government, 1976 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Guevara, Ernesto "Che,", 1989 (Folder 12: 7)
  - Human rights
    - 1967-1976 (Folder 12: 8)
    - 1977-1978 (Folder 12: 9)
  - International Monetary Fund, undated (Folder 12: 10)
  - Marxism--Bolivia, 1957 (Folder 12: 11)
  - Mining industry--Bolivia
    - Undated (Folder 12: 12)
    - 1947 (Folder 12: 13)
    - 1952 (Folder 12: 14-15)
    - 1952 (Box-folder 13: 1-5)
    - 1953-1977 (Folder 13: 6)
    - 1978-1991 (Folder 13: 7)
  - Petroleum industry--Bolivia, 1970-1997 (Folder 13: 8)
  - Political prisoners--Argentina, 1979 (Folder 13: 9)
  - Saenz, Jaime, 1986 (Folder 13: 10)
  - Sugar industry--Bolivia, undated (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Trade unions--Bolivia
    - 1944-1956 (Folder 14: 2)
    - 1965-1976 (Folder 14: 3)
    - 1977-1997 (Folder 14: 4)
  - Transportation--Bolivia, 1977-1986 (Folder 14: 5)
  - Vasquez, Noel, undated (Folder 14: 6)
  - Villarroel, Gaulberto, undated (Folder 14: 7)
- Writings by Others, 1979-1995.
  Articles and papers, arranged alphabetically by author
  - Ampuero Diaz, Raúl Galvarino, undated (Folder 14: 8)
  - Baudoin, Luis, undated (Folder 14: 9-11)
  - Capriles Villazón, Orlando, 1979 (Folder 14: 12)
  - Echazu Alvarado, Juan, 1987 (Folder 14: 13)
  - Eckstein, Susan, 1983 (Folder 14: 14)
  - Léon, Armando, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Mattos, Carlos A. de, undated (Folder 15: 2)
  - Ortíz Mercado, Róger, 1994-1995 (Folder 15: 3)
  - Paz Ballivian, Danilo, 1990 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Pereira Fiorilo, Juan, 1982 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Saavedra Weise, Agustín, 1995 (Folder 15: 6)
  - Shimose, Pedro, undated (Folder 15: 7)
  - Singer, Hans W., 1989 (Folder 15: 8)
- Printed Matter, 1956-2002.
  Monographs, newsletters, pamphlets, and serial issues, largely relating to Bolivian history and politics, arranged alphabetically by physical form and chronologically thereunder
  - Monographs
    - Undated (Folder 15: 9-14)
    - 1956 (Folder 15: 15)
    - 1959 (Folder 15: 16)
    - 1967 (Folder 15: 17)
    - 1969 (Folder 15: 18)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - 1974 (Folder 16: 2)
    - 1975 (Folder 16: 3-6)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
    - 1993 (Folder 17: 3)
    - 1994 (Folder 17: 4)
    - 1995 (Folder 17: 5)
    - 1996 (Folder 17: 6-7)
    - 1998 (Folder 17: 8-10)
    - 1999 (Folder 17: 11-12)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - 2002 (Folder 18: 2-3)
  - Newsletters
    - 1994 (Folder 18: 4)
    - 1995 (Folder 18: 5-6)
    - 1996 (Folder 18: 7-8)
    - 1997 (Folder 18: 9)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - Pamphlets
    - Undated (Folder 19: 2)
    - 1957-1961 (Folder 19: 3)
    - 1972-1977 (Folder 19: 4)
    - 1985-1987 (Folder 19: 5)
    - 1991-1995 (Folder 19: 6)
    - 1997-1998 (Folder 19: 7)
    - 1999 (Folder 19: 8)
  - Serial issues
    - 1986-1989 (Folder 19: 9)
    - 1990-1997 (Folder 19: 10)
    - 1998-2000 (Folder 19: 11)
- Photographs, 1928-2000. (Box 20)
  Prints, arranged in two groups, "Juan Lechín Oquendo" and "Others," and chronologically thereunder
  - Juan Lechín Oquendo
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo with others in a Bolivian mine, circa 1928 (Folder 20: 1)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo, circa 1950 (Folder 20: 2)
    - Eight prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo, circa 1952 (Folder 20: 3)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo with other militants of the Movimiento Nacionalista Revolucionario, circa 1952 (Folder 20: 4)
    - Three prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo during the Bolivian National Revolution, 1952 (Folder 20: 5)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo signing a decree nationalizing Bolivian mines, 1952 (Folder 20: 6)
    - Two prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo as government minister, 1953 (Folder 20: 7)
    - Four prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo, circa 1955 (Folder 20: 8)
    - One album containing sixteen prints depicting the official visit of Juan Lechín Oquendo to West Germany, 1955 November 6-10 (Folder 20: 9)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo, circa 1956 (Folder 20: 10)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo and his son Juan Claudio Lechín Weise, 1956 (Folder 20: 11)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo and his family at the baptism ceremony of Juan Claudio Lechín Weise, 1956 (Folder 20: 12)
    - Two prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo at an official reception, 1956 August 7 (Folder 20: 13)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo and his wife Nancy Weise Lechín on a visit to a Bolivian mine, circa 1958 (Folder 20: 14)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo with a group of friends, circa 1960 (Folder 20: 15)
    - Twenty-four prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo on the occasion of his inauguration as vice-president of Bolivia, 1956. (Folder 20: 16)
      Eighteen of these prints also depict the Bolivian president, Victor Paz Estenssoro
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo and Juan Domingo Peron, circa 1961 (Folder 20: 17)
    - Twenty-eight prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo in his capacity as Bolivian vice-president, circa 1961-1963 (Folder 20: 18)
    - Two prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo on an official visit to Lebanon, 1961 (Folder 20: 19)
    - Three prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo and his wife Nancy Weise Lechín on an official visit to Italy, 1961 (Folder 20: 20)
    - Two prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo on an official visit to Taiwan, 1961 (Folder 20: 21)
    - Eight prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo and his wife Nancy Weise Lechín, Taiwan, 1961 (Folder 20: 22)
    - Three prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo with Generalissimo and Madame Chiang Kai-shek, Taiwan, 1961 (Folder 20: 23)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo, Nancy Weise Lechín, and Juan Claudio Lechín Weise, circa 1962 (Folder 20: 24)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo and his wife Nancy Weise Lechín, circa 1963 (Folder 20: 25)
    - Two prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo at the founding congress of the Partido Revolucionario de Izquierda Nacional, La Paz, Bolivia, 1964 (Folder 20: 26)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo at the inaugural session of the Asamblea Popular, La Paz, Bolivia, 1970 (Folder 20: 27)
    - Two prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo and Agustín Barcelli, circa 1975 (Folder 20: 28)
    - Two prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo at a congress of Bolivian teachers, Sucre, Bolivia, 1978 October 1-5 (Folder 20: 29)
    - One contact sheet with thirty prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo and others at a meeting of the Central Obrera Boliviana, circa 1979 (Folder 20: 30)
    - Three prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo, 1981 (Folder 20: 31)
    - Two prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo at a trade union conference, 1983 (Folder 20: 32)
    - Two prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo addressing a crowd from a balcony, La Paz, Bolivia, 1983 (Folder 20: 33)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo at a meeting of the Central Obrera Boliviano, 1984 (Folder 20: 34)
    - Eight prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo, circa 1985 (Folder 20: 35)
    - One print depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo at a negotiating session between the Central Obrera Boliviano and the Bolivian government, 1985 (Folder 20: 36)
    - Fifteen prints depicting Juan Lechín Oquendo addressing rallies and participating in demonstrations, La Paz, Bolivia, 1985 (Folder 20: 37)